highend.com 2017-11-15

# Privacy policy

High End Systems Privacy Statement

This document was **last updated 10/21/2015.**

High End Systems is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring that your visit to High End Systems does not result in unwarranted third-party communiques to you in the future. You can visit most pages on our site without giving us any information about yourself. But sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this privacy statement explains data collection and use in those situations. This privacy statement only applies to High End Systems and Flyingpig webspaces- it does not apply to other online or offline High End Systems sites, products or services. Please read the complete High End Systems privacy statement.

#### Collection of Personal Information

We will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you (personal information) or allows us to contact you. Generally, this information is requested when you are registering before entering a contest, ordering e-mail newsletters, joining a limited-access site, signing up for an event or training, or when registering for High End Systems products or services.

For example: If you sign up for a drawing that requires us to ship you some product, we will request personal information necessary for billing and/or shipping, such as: name, address, telephone number, and credit card number.

When you buy and install a new product, we may ask you to register your purchase electronically. We keep this registration information on file with any information you've already given us on previous visits to our Web site.

High End Systems also collects certain information about your computer hardware and software. This information may include: your IP address, browser type, operating system, domain name, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of High End Systems.

High End Systems also collects information about which pages our customers visit within High End Systems. This site visitation data is identified only by a unique ID number, and it is never linked with personal information unless a user consents as described below.

#### Use of your Personal Information

We use your personal information for the following purposes:

•To ensure our site is relevant to your needs.   
•To deliver services, such as newsletters, events, training or software, that you request or purchase.   
•To help us create and publish content most relevant to you.   
•To alert you to product upgrades, special offers, updated information and other new services from High End Systems, if you so request.   
•To allow you access to limited-entry areas of our site as appropriate.

We will merge site-visitation data with anonymous demographic information for research purposes, and we may use this information in aggregate to provide more relevant content.

High End Systems would only ever disclose your personal information if, requested by you, required to do so by law, or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on High End Systems or the site or (b) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of High End Systems employees, users of High End Systems products or services, or members of the public.

Your information may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which High End Systems or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using this site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. High End Systems abides by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

#### Control of your Personal Information

When you register, or otherwise give us personal information, High End Systems will not share that information with third parties without your permission, other than for the limited exceptions already listed. It will only be used for the purposes stated above.

#### Access to your Personal Information

We will provide you with the means to ensure that your personal information is correct and current.

#### Security of your Personal Information

High End Systems is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide in computer servers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit sensitive information over the internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

#### Protection of Children's Personal Information

High End Systems is a general audience site and does not knowingly collect any personal information from children.

#### What About Cookies?

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and to provide certain features when you visit our site. The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. However, cookies allow you to take full advantage of some of the High End Systems site's features, and we recommend that you leave them turned on.

#### Changes to this Statement

High End Systems will occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of the privacy statement. For material changes to this statement, High End Systems will notify you by placing prominent notice on the Web site.

#### Contact Information

High End Systems welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement, please contact us electronically or via postal mail.

High End Systems Inc.   
2105 Gracy Farms Lane   
Austin, Texas 78758
